Guide to the Thomas Sieniewicz Collection of Glass Negatives of New Haven
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Thomas Sieniewicz collection of glass negatives of New Haven
1890-1890
MS 1819
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.5
(2 boxes)
The collection consists of forty-two glass negatives depicting New Haven, Connecticut, businesses and residences.
Sieniewicz, Thomas
Separated Materials
Glass negative of H. L. Brown Merchant Tailor was discarded after scanning due to condition.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection is a gift of Thomas Sieniewicz, 1998.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Existence and Location of Copies
Some glass negatives have been digitally reproduced and are available through the Manuscripts and Archives Digital Image Database (MADID).
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of forty-two glass negatives depicting New Haven, Connecticut, businesses and residences. The images are of business facades and building exteriors with individuals standing at the entrances.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two sections, Businesses and Residences, and alphabetically therein.
Architecture, Domestic -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Buildings -- Connecticut -- New Haven; New Haven (Conn.) -- Commerce; Glass negatives; Sieniewicz, Thomas
- Businesses
  - A. E. Mack, saddlery, Circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A. Sachs, dry goods, Circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Adams Express Co., Branch of the Continental Insurance Company of New York, Circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Boston Boot & Shoe Co., Circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - C. F. Clark, grocer, Circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Clerkin & McDonald, Circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Household Ranges of Clerkin & McDonald, Circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Household Ranges of Clerkin & McDonald, Circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Coal and Wood Yard, Circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Family Wine and Liquor, Circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Fisher's Café, Circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Globe Restaurant, Circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - H. L. Brown Merchant Tailor, Circa 1890; 1
    General note
    Contact Public Services (phone: 203 432-1735, e-mail: mssa.reference@yale.edu) for information on accessing this digital object.
    - Digital use copy, 1
  - Jos. E. Taylor, liquor, Circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - L. D. Chidsey & Co., Circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
  - L. H. Frost, livery, Circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - M. Franklin, confectionary, Circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Nicolazinno, ice cream and confectionary, Circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Poolroom, Circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Rothchild, carpets, wallpapers, and window shades, Circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Spargo Bro's., horse shoeing and carriage repairing, Circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - T. H. Linahan, Circa 1890 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - T. J. Shanley & Co., Circa 1890 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - T. Murray, boots and shoes, Circa 1890 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Thomas Clarke, beer, liquor, and cigars, Circa 1890 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - W. F. Foster & Co. / New Haven Window Shade Co., Circa 1890 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - William B. Kilbride, wines and liquors, Circa 1890 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - William H. Couch, saddlery / Globe Printing Works / Pickett Printer, Circa 1890 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Wm. P. Quinn, ales, wines, liquors, and cigars, Circa 1890 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Wooster A. Ensig..., Circa 1890 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Unidentified
    - Bakery [?], Circa 1890 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Fabric/clothing store [?], Circa 1890 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Liquor store [?], Circa 1890 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Saloon [?], Circa 1890 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Undertaker [?], Circa 1890 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Residences, unidentified, Circa 1890 (Box 2, Folder 15-21)